// Questions array
const questions = [
        {
        "numb": 51,
        "question": "Local signs of the intrapleural bleeding includes:",
        "answer": "attenuation of respiratory noises during auscultation",
        "options": [
            "visible narrowing of the intercostal spaces",
            "attenuation of respiratory noises during auscultation",
            "tympanitis in the lower chest",
            "dry and wet wheezing during auscultation",
            "bronchial respiration during auscultation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 52,
        "question": "At what stage of ectopic pregnancy does internal bleeding occur?",
        "answer": "8 weeks",
        "options": [
            "2 weeks",
            "6 weeks",
            "5 weeks",
            "8 weeks",
            "3 weeks"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 53,
        "question": "The place of compression of the subclavian artery is located in the area of:",
        "answer": "groin",
        "options": [
            "chest",
            "groin",
            "abdomen",
            "armpit",
            "neck"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 54,
        "question": "The methods of temporary bleeding arrest include:",
        "answer": "wound tamponade",
        "options": [
            "wound tamponade",
            "diathermocoagulation",
            "vessel ligation",
            "arterial vessel embolization",
            "hemostatic sutures on the wound"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 55,
        "question": "In case of bleeding, the axillary artery should be pressed against:",
        "answer": "the inner surface of the humerus",
        "options": [
            "the 1st rib outside of the attachment point of the sternoclavicular-nipple muscle to the collarbone",
            "the head of the humerus",
            "the inner surface of the humerus",
            "the transverse process of the 6th cervical vertebra",
            "the horizontal branch of the pubic bone"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 56,
        "question": "The biological methods of stopping bleeding include:",
        "answer": "tamponade of a wound with an omentum",
        "options": [
            "vascular suture to an arterial vessel",
            "clamping a vessel",
            "applying a tourniquet to a limb",
            "tamponade of a wound with an omentum",
            "ligation of a vessel in a wound"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 57,
        "question": "Staff donors are donors who:",
        "answer": "systematically participate in donation for several years",
        "options": [
            "have a rare blood type",
            "immunized donors with a certain antigen",
            "donate blood when there is a need for an institution",
            "donate blood regularly",
            "systematically participate in donation for several years"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 58,
        "question": "Blood preparations include:",
        "answer": "prothrombin complex",
        "options": [
            "leuco mass",
            "thrombo mass",
            "plasma",
            "erythro mass",
            "prothrombin complex"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 59,
        "question": "The regulators of the water-salt balance include:",
        "answer": "Ringer's solution",
        "options": [
            "lipofundin",
            "hemodesis",
            "gelatinol",
            "rheopolyglucin",
            "Ringer's solution"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 60,
        "question": "Hemotransfusion reactions include:",
        "answer": "fever",
        "options": [
            "septic shock",
            "thromboembolism",
            "fever",
            "homologous blood syndrome",
            "hemotransfusion shock"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 61,
        "question": "Hemotransfusion complications of a technical nature include:",
        "answer": "acute dilation of the heart",
        "options": [
            "citrate intoxication",
            "massive transfusion syndrome",
            "acute dilation of the heart",
            "allergic",
            "antigenic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 62,
        "question": "Hemodilution is:",
        "answer": "a method of blood dilution",
        "options": [
            "a method of direct blood transfusion",
            "a method of exchange blood transfusion",
            "autohemotransfusion",
            "autoplasmotransfusion",
            "a method of blood dilution"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 63,
        "question": "What is the name of the antigen-antibody reaction in determining the blood Rh-factor?",
        "answer": "isoagglutination",
        "options": [
            "isoagglutination",
            "heteroagglutination",
            "pseuodagglutination",
            "hemagglutination",
            "panagglutination"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 64,
        "question": "What is the necessary temperature regime (in degrees Celsius) when determining the blood type according to the ABO system?",
        "answer": "15-25",
        "options": [
            "(12-14)",
            "(5-8)",
            "46-48",
            "26-38",
            "15-25"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 65,
        "question": "When determining the blood type, the drop of blood should be less a drop of coliclone:",
        "answer": "five to ten times",
        "options": [
            "ten times",
            "three times",
            "five to ten times",
            "five times",
            "twenty times"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 66,
        "question": "Blood sampling to determine compatibility according to the ABO system and the Rh factor is performed from:",
        "answer": "veins in a dry test tube",
        "options": [
            "finger on a slide with the addition of sodium citrate",
            "a finger on a slide",
            "veins in melanger",
            "veins in a test tube with isotonic sodium chloride solution",
            "veins in a dry test tube"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 67,
        "question": "When preparing patients for hemotransfusion, it is necessary to:",
        "answer": "do all of the above",
        "options": [
            "collect a blood transfusion history",
            "do all of the above",
            "do a general blood test",
            "do a general urine test",
            "collect an obstetric history"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 68,
        "question": "What do they do with a bottle that has been released after transfusion of blood and its components?",
        "answer": "leave 10-15 ml of blood in a bottle and store for 2 days",
        "options": [
            "leave 10-15 ml of blood in a bottle and store until the patient is discharged",
            "they throw it away",
            "leave 10-15 ml of blood in a bottle and store for 30 days",
            "leave 10-15 ml of blood in a bottle and store for 2 days",
            "they wash it and take it to the laboratory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 69,
        "question": "Drugs that promote blood clotting are called:",
        "answer": "coagulants",
        "options": [
            "none of the above",
            "anticoagulants",
            "coagulants",
            "oxidants",
            "antioxidants"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 70,
        "question": "Blood enzyme elements that promote blood clotting:",
        "answer": "platelets",
        "options": [
            "white blood cells",
            "platelets",
            "red blood cells",
            "globulins",
            "basophils"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 71,
        "question": "Direct-acting hemostatics include:",
        "answer": "calcium chloride",
        "options": [
            "heparin",
            "calcium chloride",
            "nicoumalone",
            "tinzaparin sodium",
            "vikasol"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 72,
        "question": "Non-direct action hemostatics include:",
        "answer": "all listed",
        "options": [
            "vikasol",
            "vitamin K",
            "phytomenadione",
            "all listed",
            "rutin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 73,
        "question": "Anticoagulants of non-direct action include:",
        "answer": "dicumarin",
        "options": [
            "trypsin",
            "vikasol",
            "dicumarin",
            "heparin",
            "fibrinolysin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 74,
        "question": "In what concentration is thrombin administered intravenously?",
        "answer": "10%",
        "options": [
            "10%",
            "40%",
            "50%",
            "30%",
            "20%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 75,
        "question": "The temperature regime for determining the blood type:",
        "answer": "15-25C",
        "options": [
            "5-8C",
            "12-14C",
            "25-30C",
            "15-25C",
            "10-12C"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 76,
        "question": "The result of the agglutination reaction in determining the blood group according to standard serums is determined by:",
        "answer": "3 min",
        "options": [
            "10 min",
            "1 min",
            "2 min",
            "5 min",
            "3 min"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 77,
        "question": "To stabilize donated blood, use:",
        "answer": "2.6% sodium citrate solution",
        "options": [
            "2.6% sodium citrate solution",
            "isotonic solution",
            "albumin",
            "glucose",
            "glycerin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 78,
        "question": "During blood transfusion, the patient's condition worsened, the pain appeared in the lower back and behind the sternum. This indicates:",
        "answer": "blood transfusion shock",
        "options": [
            "hemorrhagic shock",
            "blood transfusion shock",
            "citrate shock",
            "pyrogenic reaction",
            "allergic reaction"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 79,
        "question": "Features of intravenous administration of protein hydralizates:",
        "answer": "no biological sample is required",
        "options": [
            "they are injected droply 20-30 per minute",
            "they are injected in a jet",
            "a biological sample is required",
            "they are injected droply 50-60 per minute",
            "no biological sample is required"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 80,
        "question": "In case of hemorrhagic shock, first of all, the patient should be transfused:",
        "answer": "platelet mass",
        "options": [
            "plasma",
            "polyglucine",
            "erythrocyte mass",
            "whole blood",
            "platelet mass"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 81,
        "question": "Operations related to bloodless are:",
        "answer": "dislocation reduction, bone fragments reposition",
        "options": [
            "laparotomy, thoracotomy",
            "dislocation reduction, bone fragments reposition",
            "lymph node biopsy",
            "trial laparotomy",
            "endoscopic cholecystectomy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 82,
        "question": "An operational technique is:",
        "answer": "removal of the affected organ",
        "options": [
            "Filonchikov-Grossich skin treatment",
            "operative reception",
            "removal of the affected organ",
            "skin dissection",
            "suturing the skin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 83,
        "question": "Endoscopic surgeries are:",
        "answer": "operations performed using endoscopic devices",
        "options": [
            "operations performed under X-ray control",
            "operations performed with a microscope",
            "operations after which endoscopic control is required",
            "operations performed laparoscopically",
            "operations performed using endoscopic devices"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 84,
        "question": "Endovascular surgery is:",
        "answer": "intravascular operations performed under X-ray control",
        "options": [
            "operations performed using endoscopic devices",
            "operations performed with a microscope",
            "operations after which endoscopic control is required",
            "intravascular operations performed under X-ray control",
            "operations performed on the main vessels"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 85,
        "question": "Requirements for surgical access are:",
        "answer": "minimal injjuries",
        "options": [
            "the distance from the surface of the body to the exposed organ should be minimal",
            "access should provide a wide exposure of the pathological focus",
            "large injuries",
            "minimal injjuries",
            "the length of the skin incision should not exceed 20 cm"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 86,
        "question": "Diagnostic operations include:",
        "answer": "lymph node biopsy",
        "options": [
            "correction of dislocation of the shoulder",
            "appendectomy",
            "autopsy of the panaritium",
            "lymph node biopsy",
            "herniation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 87,
        "question": "Operations are distinguished by urgency:",
        "answer": "emergency, urgent, planned",
        "options": [
            "radical, planned, palliative",
            "planned, emergency, multi-stage",
            "diagnostic, non-urgent, one-stage",
            "emergency, urgent, palliative",
            "emergency, urgent, planned"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 88,
        "question": "Operational access includes the following stages of the operation:",
        "answer": "skin dissection",
        "options": [
            "removal of the affected organ",
            "suturing the skin",
            "Filonchikov-Grossich skin treatment",
            "surgery, stopping bleeding",
            "skin dissection"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 89,
        "question": "Emergency surgery is indicated when:",
        "answer": "perforated stomach ulcer",
        "options": [
            "perforated stomach ulcer",
            "varicose veins of the lower extremities",
            "trophic ulcer",
            "liver cancer",
            "lipoma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 90,
        "question": "Prevention of thromboembolic complications after surgery includes:",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "options": [
            "all of the above",
            "getting up early",
            "the use of anticoagulants",
            "the use of disaggregants",
            "bandaging of the lower extremities with an elastic bandage"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 91,
        "question": "Additional complaints of the patient are caused by:",
        "answer": "concomitant pathology",
        "options": [
            "concomitant pathology",
            "complications of the underlying disease",
            "underlying disease",
            "increased pain syndrome",
            "change in the patient's state of health"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 92,
        "question": "The patient's complaint of pain in dislocation of the shoulder is:",
        "answer": "main",
        "options": [
            "main",
            "basic",
            "primary",
            "additional",
            "secondary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 93,
        "question": "The examination of the patient begins with:",
        "answer": "clarification of complaints",
        "options": [
            "clarification of the history of the disease",
            "clarification of complaints",
            "life history",
            "objective research",
            "an external examination"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 94,
        "question": "Data from previous additional research methods  are described in the medical history section:",
        "answer": "the history of the development of the disease",
        "options": [
            "results of additional research methods",
            "general objective research",
            "the history of the development of the disease",
            "general information about the patient",
            "life history"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 95,
        "question": "An increase in body temperature in acute appendicitis is complaint:",
        "answer": "secondary",
        "options": [
            "general",
            "basic",
            "additional",
            "main",
            "secondary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 96,
        "question": "The allergic history is reflected in the section of medical history:",
        "answer": "life history",
        "options": [
            "history of the disease",
            "life history",
            "additional examination",
            "complaints",
            "general objective examination"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 97,
        "question": "How should the insurance history be described in the medical history?",
        "answer": "indicate the place of work and the presence (absence) of the disability sheet on hand",
        "options": [
            "indicate the total insurance premium of the patient for the entire time",
            "specify the annual insurance deductions from wages",
            "specify the amount of the maximum insurance payment",
            "list the insurance companies in which the patient was insured",
            "indicate the place of work and the presence (absence) of the disability sheet on hand"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 98,
        "question": "Description of the local status of a patient with acute appendicitis implies:",
        "answer": "a detailed description of the results of an objective examination of the entire digestive system",
        "options": [
            "a detailed description of the patient's complaints",
            "a detailed description of the results of additional research",
            "a description of the specific symptoms of acute appendicits",
            "a detailed description of the results of an objective examination of the entire digestive system",
            "a description of the development of the disease in chronological order"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 99,
        "question": "The clinical diagnosis in emergency patients should be formulated:",
        "answer": "during the first day",
        "options": [
            "immediately upon admission",
            "within 12 hours",
            "during the first day",
            "within the next 6 hours",
            "after 3 days"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 100,
        "question": "Information about the reason for the patient's current hospitalization described in the medical history section:",
        "answer": "history of the development of the present disease",
        "options": [
            "history of the development of the present disease",
            "results of additional examination",
            "complaints",
            "life history",
            "local status"
        ]
    },
    ];
